<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>The Birds and the Bees</name>
  <author>Fluffy</author>
  <url>https://ludeon.com/forums/index.php?topic=15964.0</url>
  <description>Adds reproductive organs to the animals, and then you, raiders and time can take them away again. 

&lt;b&gt;Does NOT require a new save game&lt;/b&gt; 
Should be fine to use with any other mod that adds animals, races, relations, or anything else. However, you can’t remove the mod from a game.

&lt;size=24&gt;Features&lt;/size&gt;
Animals (including humanoids) require reproductive organs to mate &amp; and do lovin’. 


Adds reproductive organs to fleshy pawns (e.g., animals and colonists). 
Since reproductive organs are now a body part, they can be affected by external violence - including, but not limited to; gunfire, berserking colonists, frostbite, castration (neutering) and old age.
Reworks mating &amp; lovin’ to take account of fertility stat. 
Adds old age diseases related to fertility (menopause, infertility) that can affect both fertility and mood.

&lt;size=24&gt;Known issues&lt;/size&gt;

Neutering always requires medicine. This is a vanilla thing (the same thing happens with euthanasia), and I’ve not had the time to trace it down and fix it. Pull requests welcome!

&lt;size=24&gt;Powered by Harmony&lt;/size&gt;


&lt;size=24&gt;Does this mod add the ability for colonists to have babies?&lt;/size&gt;
&lt;i&gt;No. Nor will I ever add this, so don’t ask.&lt;/i&gt;
There’s a myriad of problems with adding colonist babies. There’s moral/ethical issues, but I don’t particularly care about those, I don’t see why making baby leather hats is worse than prisoner leather hats. 

What I do care about is gameplay. For me, two things are required to make babies actually fun. 

First, there needs to be systems around babies. If they’re just colonists or animals in behaviour, I don’t see the point. You’d have to have various interactions from parents with their children, amongst children, children with the environment, etc. etc. to really bring children alive. Then you’d also want to build in things like schools or at least some sort of internships/apprenticeships, the list goes on and on. 
The problem with all of this is that it takes a huge amount of work - including a number of new gameplay mechanics. It’s something better suited for Tynan himself to add to the game. 

Second, the timescale just doesn’t work. The average colony will last a couple of years, 10 if you’re in it for the long haul. Only rarely do colonies last longer than that. That would mean that there’s not really any room for progression, and I don’t see the fun in that. Adding cloning vats, time chambers, gro-quick drugs or whatever are weak solutions for a fundamental problem, and I don’t want to go that way. Changing the games timescale is pretty much impossible for mods to do. 

&lt;i&gt;TLDR; if you want babies, go ask Tynan.&lt;/i&gt;

&lt;size=24&gt;Contributors&lt;/size&gt;

kouyou:    Japanese translation
Duduluu:    Chinese translations
Jdalt40:    remove obsolete abstract defs
rw-chaos:    German translation
shiuanyue:    Chinese translations
Han Yaodong:    Simplified Chinese translation
gast:    

&lt;size=24&gt;Version&lt;/size&gt;
This is version 3.7.57, for RimWorld 1.1.2610.

</description>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.1</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <packageId>fluffy.thebirdsandthebees</packageId>
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
      <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
      <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
  </loadAfter>
</ModMetaData>